<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>conference on Leipzig Gophers</title>
    <link>https://golangleipzig.space/tags/conference/</link>
    <description>Recent content in conference on Leipzig Gophers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:30:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://golangleipzig.space/tags/conference/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>GoLab 2025</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/golab-2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Jul 2025 11:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/golab-2025/</guid>
      <description>GoLab 2025 Since 2015, Develer has been organizing one of the best Go conferences on the continent: GoLab - bringing together the international and Italian Go developer community in the beautiful city of Florence. Happy 10th birthday, GoLab!
This year, GoLab will take place Oct 5-7, 2025!
Thoughtfulness in environmental stewardship and social responsibility continues with GoLab 2025 through their GoLab for the Planet initiative.
The conference offers a variety of topics and formats:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOLAB 2024</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/golab-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 11:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/golab-2024/</guid>
      <description>GOLAB 2024 GOLAB, The International Conference on Go is a wonderful event that brings together developers from Europe and beyond in Florence, Italy since 2015 and which will take place 2024-11-11 to 2024-11-13 this year, featuring a discovery and deep dive track as well as workshops on introductory and advanced topics. Find out more:
Conference homepage: golab.io GOLAB on Twitter GOLAB YouTube Channel, recordings from previous years We partnered with GOLAB and are excited to share discount codes for tickets 🎟️ — just drop by our next event!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go at devopenspace 2023</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-devopenspace-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-devopenspace-2023/</guid>
      <description>devopenspace is a regular, classic unconference on software engineering and related topics - this year, there are a few Go and cloud related workshops as well! See the agenda for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLT23</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/clt23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/clt23/</guid>
      <description>CLT23 We briefly presented at the annual Chemnitz Linux Days (CLT) conference on 2023-03-11. The topic was Sustainability and Security in the Go ecosystem, collecting a few thoughts starting from the ACM Queue article Surviving Software Dependencies (2019).
Keywords: security, data breach, dependency management, distributed package management, OSV, vulnerability scanning.
We prepared a demo for the vanity URL import supported by Go package system - check out clt23 or try:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Storage Summit Berlin</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/decentralized-storage-summit-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/decentralized-storage-summit-berlin/</guid>
      <description>In Meetup #4 we learned about a Go project using the Lightning Network. Many more projects in the Cryptocurrenty space use Go, such filecoin, subprojects from sia and many more.
If you are excited about these technologies, why not attend the Decentralized Storage Summit at TU Berlin on Friday, August 23, 2019?
Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to a discount code to get in for free:
https://www.eventbrite.com/e/decentralised-storage-summit-tickets-62719912948?discount=DC2 Enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
