<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>summary on Leipzig Gophers</title>
    <link>https://golangleipzig.space/tags/summary/</link>
    <description>Recent content in summary on Leipzig Gophers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 10:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://golangleipzig.space/tags/summary/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #41 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-41-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-41-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Go 1.22 and more Hybrid Meetup #41 took place 2024-02-27 at Basislager Leipzig. We reviewed some updates in Go 1.22, especially the sharing bug fix in for loops and the enhanced routing pattern.
Go tools for genai models There is no shortage of tooling and applications for LLM and generative AI in general, and increasingly, these tools abstract the model access away to you can use remote or local models with the same code (and easily switch between different providers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #40 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-40-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-40-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Domain Driven Data Oriented Design Hybrid Meetup #40 took place 2024-01-30 at Basislager Leipzig and we had a great presentation by Bill Kennedy from Ardan Labs about Domain Driven Data Oriented Design. A recording of the talk is available at our YouTube Channel.

All code shown in the talk is available at: ardanlabs/service.
Just a few notes from the talk:
 CRUD is boilerplate domain-driven design comes with a cost but can help to keep larger projects structured and maintainable one way to limit data exposure per domain is to create a relational view per domain example of an opaque type from the repo is user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎄 Drinkup #39 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-39-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-39-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Drinkup notes Meetup #39 took place 2023-12-19 at Cantona Leipzig and these were just some of the talking points.
 without extra libraries, schema validation in JSON is minimalistic (e.g. json schema); could cue help? malloy is an experimental data modeling language over relational stores direnv is a nice shell helper for 12-factor-style appu time is not just a line, it&amp;rsquo;s bound (cf. chrony) test your latencies: aws, gcp, or just the internet eventbridge/kubernetes at serverless office hours interesting, dedicated code assistant for ansible: Ansible Lightspeed  Next year will probably bring yet another wave of hyper-focussed LLM-based code comprehension tools (beside hyper-focussed niche, local, custom-trained LLMs for dedicated tasks, in general).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #38 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-38-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-38-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>A cache is worth a thousand searches Hybrid meetup #38 took place 2023-11-20 19:00 at CHECK24 Leipzig Office.
We had a great presentation from Fabian about building a mission critical query caching database (MemoryDB) in Go and the challenges involved.
One challenge is the variety of query parameters and nearly overlapping values and ranges. A key for performance is to express various parameter values (e.g. date boundaries) with the help of BitMaps, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #37 notice</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-37-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-37-notice/</guid>
      <description>Free Form Meetup #37 Since starting Leipzig Gophers almost four years ago we always aimed at connecting people and to learn about interesting Go projects and we had a lot of fun organizing that. Meetup #37 on 2023-09-26 aimed to be a free-form event, that is an event without a defined agenda with an opportunity to meet and discuss.
We&amp;rsquo;ll try to sharpen the free-form event format in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #36 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-36-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-36-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Cut Cloud Complexity with Encore Hybrid meetup #36 took place 2023-06-20 19:00 at Basislager Leipzig.
We had a great presentation from André Eriksson about Encore - a platform written in Go and for Go for radically simplifying cloud-native backend development.
Beside motivation and overview, André live-coded an uptime monitoring service, ran it locally and deployed it onto Google Cloud within a few minutes. A recording of the talk is available on YouTube!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #35 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-35-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-35-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Cgo experiments Hybrid meetup #35 took place 2023-04-18 19:00 at Basislager Leipzig and was all about Cgo.
Cgo allows to bridge C and Go. From C, we can connect to other languages, like C++, too. Use cases are legacy code or performance. Implementing a pseudo-random walk (using an LCG) in both Go and C shows that C can be up to 4x faster for this particular task.
C 1 -1 29.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLT23</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/clt23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/clt23/</guid>
      <description>CLT23 We briefly presented at the annual Chemnitz Linux Days (CLT) conference on 2023-03-11. The topic was Sustainability and Security in the Go ecosystem, collecting a few thoughts starting from the ACM Queue article Surviving Software Dependencies (2019).
Keywords: security, data breach, dependency management, distributed package management, OSV, vulnerability scanning.
We prepared a demo for the vanity URL import supported by Go package system - check out clt23 or try:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #34 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-34-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-34-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Go 1.20 Hybrid meetup #34 took place 2023-02-21 19:00 at Basislager Leipzig and was all about Go 1.20 (similar to previous years, where we looked at Go 1.14, 1.16, 1.18 - #9, #16, #25).
We had two great presentations:
 A rundown of most novelties in Go 1.20: Go 1.20 updates, including many examples &amp;ndash; thanks, Andreas! &amp;hellip; and Go 1.20 Coverage Profiling Support for Kubernetes Apps, a walkthrough on how to use Go 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Drinkup #33 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-33-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 20:00:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-33-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Drinkup Notes We met 2022-12-20 19:00 at Café Cantona, with no specific Go agenda, for a great exchange of ideas and experiences - too many to capture them in a blog post, so here&amp;rsquo;s just a fraction of the topics we passed (slightly categorized):
Reading list  Grokking Functional Programming - a very readable introduction to the topic; more academic angles include the classic Out of the tar pit or Purely Functional Data Structures (always nice to find references to this book in code) in 04/2022, a JS version of SICP (1984) came out: SICP JS edition, there&amp;rsquo;s an open access version, too Podman in Action, container tools with a nice Unix backdrop the classic, albeit just five year old DDIA 100 mistakes in Go and how to avoid them - actionable advice for Go code improvements  Software General  ISO 28500:2017, aka WARC is how you can capture the web - and there are many libraries and tools around this format, just to name a few: Heritrix, brozzler, webrecorder, warcprox, replayweb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #32 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-32-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 13:00:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-32-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Gridfuse x Leipzig Gophers Leipzig Gophers #32 took place on 2022-11-29 19:00 CET and we had a great meetup at Gridfuse&#39; new office in the heart of Leipzig. Gridfuse was founded in 2022 and builds software to bundle renewable energy sources (wind, solar, &amp;hellip;) to react to market prices - in Germany and Europe.
Predicting future energy prices is one key component, and renewables pose their own set of challenges since they depend more on external factors (like the weather, and more&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #31 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-31-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 13:00:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-31-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Personal Cloud On 2022-10-18 19:00 CEST we had our #31 meetup, this time at Basislager Coworking and with a hybrid setup (that still needs some improvement, but we&amp;rsquo;re getting there).
Max Eusterbrock and his colleague Aavash Shrestha told us about The personal cloud and the monster that makes it. In this presentation they gave us a preview on one of their new platforms that provides one-click hosting of applications, which they demonstrated with the deployment of a note taking service.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid meetup #30 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-30-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-30-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Secure data with immudb - a fast, immutable database Leipzig Gophers Hybrid Meetup #30 took place 2022-09-20 19:00 CEST at Lancaster University Leipzig Campus.
We had a great presentation by Dennis Zimmer and Bartłomiej Święcki (GitHub) from CodeNotary about their cutting edge, open source, immutable database project immudb.
Presentation slides are available here:

Originally, the CodeNotary team looked at blockchains to implement the idea of tamperproof data store - but found that they could build something more performant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Drinkup #29 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-29-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-29-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>All things Go and beyond We met on 2022-07-14 at Soltmann Bar and it was great to see everyone in person and also to welcome new Gophers.
In September, we hope to follow up with an in-person meetup featuring a presentation from immudb:
 immudb is database with built-in cryptographic proof and verification. It can track changes in sensitive data and the integrity of the history will be protected by the clients, without the need to trust the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #28 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-28-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-28-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Errors and Glamour Meetup #28 took place on 2022-06-21 19:00 CEST virtually and was one of our most visited meetup to date - thank you all for dropping by.
We had a short presentation Never forget to handle errors, rediscovered the 1000th time by Leandro from Lightmeter (gitlab, job) about a few ways to handle errors in Go. The compiler does not complain about unchecked errors, but some linters do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #27 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-27-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-27-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Algorithm Challenge Meetup #27 took place on 2022-05-10 19:00 CEST and was virtual again and we had an interesting problem-solving live-coding challenge.
Slides and code: gitlab.com/telo_tade/prefix_suffix_arrays
Problem  You are given a list of numbers. Find its longest slice that sums to zero.
 First, clarify:
 Is it a consecutive list of numbers? What kind of numbers, and how many?  We collaboratively went from a naive O(n^3) solution to a slightly improved O(n^2) one using an auxiliary data structure: a prefix sum array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #26 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-26-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-26-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Type Signatures and Cloud Storage Meetup #26 was virtual again and we were glad to meet Gophers from Leipzig and beyond. We had a two short talks and code walkthroughs on type signatures and rclone, a cloud storage tool.
Type Signatures How would you generate a unique fingerprint for a type? A fingerprint that would change, even if the name of the type stays the same, but e.g. fields in a struct are renamed, added or removed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #25 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-25-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-25-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Go 1.18 and generics Meetup #25 was virtual and we were glad to have an international audience again.
We had a great presentation about the upcoming Go 1.18 release, including generics and fuzzing:
 Go 1.18 with some fuzzing and a focus on generics  As always, Go 1.18 will include lots of smaller tweaks and improvements, like a new debug/buildinfo package, which
 provides access to information embedded in a Go binary about how it was built,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #24 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-24-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-24-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Quiz night! Thanks everyone for joining our quiz night at virtual meetup #24, Dec 21, 2021; we got through 16 of our 24 prepared questions - from easy to hard. Most prizes are already on their way.
A special thanks 💕 to our sponsors:
 O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media Manning Publications About You (check out jobs) Jetbrains  Happy holidays!
 Join our meetup to get notified of upcoming events!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #23 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-23-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-23-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Summary Meetup #23, Nov 23, 2021, originally planned on-site at Sciendis, moved online again, due to the pandemic regulations.
We had two input presentations, one about Go in a startup environment at Sciendis and reasons why Go may be a good choice. And one lightning talk about a data web service.
Go in a startup environment Sciendis develops a React Native application called Wundera with the backend service being written in Go, in a classic cloud setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #22 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-22-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-22-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Confidential Computing with Go We had a great presentation by Moritz Eckert from edgeless systems about Confidential Computing with Go, and especially ego.dev, a modified Go compiler and additional tooling which allows you to run code within a trusted execution environment like Intel® SGX enclaves with zero code changes.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a recording of the talk, code walkthroughs and Q&amp;amp;A:

A few highlights from the talk:
 a trusted execution environment can be implemented in various ways, Intel SGX being one that is usable today (with others in development, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #21 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-21-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-21-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Concise Encoding We had a great presentation about Concise Encoding, a proposed encoding standard that aims to be human and machine friendly.
 Presentation: go-concise-encoding  Here&amp;rsquo;s a recording:

Concise encoding is element-oriented (similar to e.g. JSON) and tries to solve some issues in existing standards, such as lack of types, performance and security (one similar format is Amazon Ion).
In prerelease stage, feedback is highly appreciated, a reference implementation written in Go exists at:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #20 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-20-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-20-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>We keep this short, as there would be too many interesting things to mention that come up, if curious and fun people meet.
Just to name a few things: https://twitter.com/embano1/status/1417599138796118016, Cue and Automerge (JS), &amp;hellip;
A couple of people had distant memories of Pascal, which also influenced Go e.g. in declarations or conditions without parentheses.
Many people use vscode or vim, but there are also some dedicated Go IDEs, e.g. GoLand or liteide:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #19 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-19-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-19-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Journey to the Center of Kubernetes Meetup #19 took place Jun 22, 2021 19:00 CEST, and was virtual again. Michael Gasch gave an input presentation on etcd and did a deep dive into its role in the container-orchestrator kubernetes.
The talk is based on a blog post: Onwards to the Core: etcd. A shell transcript can be found here:
 https://git.io/JnQ1n  We learned about the API of etcd, its data model, key value stores layouts, append-only storage and compaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #18 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-18-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-18-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Seeking Data Meetup #18 took place May 25, 2021 19:00 CEST, and was virtual again. We continued the data and storage supertopic for this year had a lightning talk called Seeking Data.
We looked at a few patterns when working with data, e.g. I/O considerations, what kernel hackers think about the memory hierarchy, working with large scale data at rest, or how to speed up container startup times (via lazy pulling).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #17 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-17-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-17-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>(Fuzzy) Matching with command line tools and Go Meetup #17 took place Apr 20, 2021 19:00 CEST, and was virtual again (crossing one year of virtual meetups). We had a lightning talk on a data engineering topic:
 (Fuzzy) Matching with command line tools and Go  How to build a graph dataset with about 1B edges from semi-structured data? With Taco Bell style programming, you can reuse (UNIX) command line tools and combine it with a few custom Go programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #16 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-16-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-16-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Go 1.16 Meetup #16 was all about Go 1.16 (which was released after the meetup).
We had an informative breakdown of the updates coming in this release, the full slides can be found here:
 A quick tour of Go 1.16  A few highlights are: the go tool is now module aware by default, ioutil gets deprecated, support for file embedding (we talked about that in #14) and there is a new io subpackage io/fs, defining among other things interfaces for filesystems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #15 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-15-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-15-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Concurrent woes We had two input presentations, both involving concurrent constructs.
First, we heard from the author of package waitgroup about problems with concurrent code, waitgroups and shutdowns (especially in cloud native and serverless scenarios). The basic problem: At shutdown time, you want to be graceful, but at the same time enforce a hard timeout on a number of processes running (and potentially joining in a wg.Wait).
Enter package waitgroup which allows to preempt running goroutines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #14 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-14-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-14-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>File Embedding We had a great input presentation on file embedding, which allows to ship additional files within a binary.
How do you put files into a binary? There a numerous tools, some of them limited, some of them with large feature sets.
Is it time for Yet Another File Embedding Tool? Yes!
That such a tool can be simple and easy to use is shown by klingtnet/embed.
Misc  awsls is a tool that uses code generation to simplify AWS command line interactions we side-tracked into note-taking, and found out that people use all kinds of journal software, from OneNote, plain text files, custom software and plain paper notebooks   Join us next time!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #13 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-13-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-13-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Today we had two input presentations:
 Haystack and seaweedfs: https://github.com/miku/haystack Functional Options Pattern: https://github.com/embano1/funcy-ops  Haystack The haystack talk gave an overview about an early Facebook photo storage system and a Go project inspired by it, called seaweedfs. The seaweedfs project is great, as it is developer friendly, scales up and down and is easy to use out of the box. It offers an S3 compatible API and a FUSE filesystem option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #12 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-12-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-12-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>We had a short talk about HTTP proxies in Go. As expected, Go supports the usual environment variables, like HTTP_PROXY, HTTPS_PROXY and NO_PROXY - and you can easily customize the proxy selection, as we saw in an example code walkthrough of an ip rotation proxy.
The x/net package contains support in x/net/http/httpproxy.
A couple of fun facts from the talk:
 The first book on HTTP proxies was published in 1998: &amp;ldquo;Web Proxy Servers&amp;rdquo; by Ari Luotonen (CERN), who also wrote a web proxy tunneling draft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #11 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-11-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-11-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Kubeflow  The data science process is not free of friction, especially when acquiring, preparing and cleaning data. But even when data is readily available, one might want to use it to train a number of ML models to perform model selection.
And what happens, if an update is available and the whole process needs to be run again? Optimally with a tested model that is put into production in a canary deployment workflow?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #10 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-10-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-10-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 The sync package  Virtual Meetup #10 took place on Friday, April 17, 2020, 19:00 CEST via Zoom (thanks to saschagrunert and CNCF).
Michael prepared a great overview of the sync and x/sync packages, which implement concurrency related facilities (concurrency is hard with either classical approaches or CSP, as we learned from a presentation last year at meetup #2).
The overview included among other things a bug hunt in a counter example and a benchmark of the builtin map and sync.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #9 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-9-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-9-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Go 1.14  Meetup #9 took place on Friday, February 21, 2020, 19:00 CEST at Basislager.
We looked at changes coming in the upcoming Go 1.14 release, which is is expected to be released in February 2020.
The slides can be found here:
 Slides, Repo  
There are many improvements, just one of them is lower-cost defer statements.
The proposal can be found here:
 Proposal: Low-cost defers through inline code, and extra funcdata to manage the panic case  Recommended podcast: gotime/112.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #8 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-8-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-8-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Anatomy of a Go module proxy  The Go packaging story started many years ago with GO15VENDOREXPERIMENT and a myriad of tools for managing dependencies. And, annoyingly GOPATH was one of the main obstactles for people getting started with Go. Since Go 1.11, we have experimental support for Go modules.
A new component related to modules is the module proxy. A bit of history, internals and pitfalls has been compiled by klingtnet into a great talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #7 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-7-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-7-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Concurrency in Go  Concurrency is hard, but the primitive building blocks of CSP in Go - goroutines and channels - can make things simpler.
We glanced at the six chapters of Concurrency in Go, and learned a bit about the problem setting, goroutine sizes, context switch times and patterns.
The notes can be found here:
 Notes on Concurrency in Go  In the book, the perf tool is used to benchmark context switch times of the kernel - and to compare it with context switch times in the Go scheduler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #6 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-6-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-6-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Where to Go?  The Berlin Go User Group celebrates its eighth birthday next week. Our meetup just completed its first ½ year - so far, we touched upon quite a few of the initial topic ideas.
As for Go conferences, Golab is an annual international Go conference, which will have its 4th edition this October. We have two free tickets for you - if you are interested, just drop me a line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #5 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-5-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-5-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Bits from the IO package  The IO package is a central package in the standard library, as it provides (among other things) two main interfaces:
 io.Reader io.Writer  In a lightning talk we dug a bit into the package:
 Slides (PDF) Repo  The IO model is simple and powerful (and reminds one of UNIX pipes).
🔗 Automate the Web with chromedp  In a code walkthrough we explored chromedp, a pure Go library talking the Chrome devtools protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #4 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-4-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-4-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Lightning Network Micropayments  Go is popular in the crypocurrency space. The well-rounded standard library and great support for networking applications might be one reason. In Meetup #4 Philipp presented an introduction to Bitcoin, Lighting Network and a Go project, that makes micropayments for API usage really simple: ln-paywall.
The presentation is available as PDF.
An http middleware takes care of creating invoices per request, a complete example can be implemented in a few lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #3 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-3-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 23:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-3-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Meetup #3 took place on Friday, April 12, 2019, 19:00 CEST at Basislager. We are now officially part of the Go Developer Network (GDN, currently 103 groups with 47418 members in 37 countries), which was announced in March 2019.
 The GDN is a collection of Go user groups working together with a shared mission to empower developer communities with the knowledge, experience, and wisdom to build the next generation of software in Go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second meetup wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/second-meetup-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 13:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/second-meetup-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Our second meetup took place yesterday (2019-03-15) at Basislager Leipzig, here&amp;rsquo;s a short wrap-up:
  miku gave a lightning talk about generating Go structs from JSON and XML documents, e.g. via JSONGen or zek. Code generation is not perfect, but can save you time.
  Michael presented the paper Understanding Real-World Concurrency Bugs in Go, which compares bug classes by analyzing popular open source projects like BoltDB, etcd, Docker and Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launched 🚀</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:15:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-launched/</guid>
      <description>We launched! The first meetup took place yesterday (2019-02-08) at Basislager. A dozen gophers, programmers, devops developers, cluster admins and curious individuals followed our invitation.
A good mix of backgrounds, experience levels and professional contexts lead to lively discussions around Go, the language, microservices, company cultures, adoption, streaming, cruise ships, conference impressions, book tips, distributed denial-of-service attacks, kubernetes operators and much more. Thanks for joining us, we think we&amp;rsquo;re off to a good start!</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
