<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Leipzig Gophers</title>
    <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Leipzig Gophers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 13:28:29 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://golangleipzig.space/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #44 Invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-44-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Aug 2024 13:28:29 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-44-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For meetup #44 on Tuesday Sep 24, 2024 19:00 CET we&amp;rsquo;ll showcase your daily development tools.
In this format we&amp;rsquo;ll exchange our favorite tools to do our development tasks, including
 Your favorite software tools that streamline your coding process. Custom scripts or functions you’ve written to automate repetitive tasks. Any hardware or desk setup that boosts your productivity. Even non-technical items that contribute to your coding routine are welcome!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go Tech Lunch Dates 2024</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-tech-lunch-dates-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Jul 2024 00:20:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-tech-lunch-dates-2024/</guid>
      <description>Go Tech Lunch 🍜 In addition to our regular meetups, we are trying something else and lightweight: meeting over lunch twice a month. The next dates in 2024 are:
 August 14, 2024  August 28, 2024   September 11, 2024 September 25, 2024 October 9, 2024 October 23, 2024 November 6, 2024 November 20, 2024 December 4, 2024 December 18, 2024  We always meet 12:15 CET at Pholosophy, (map, google maps).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #43 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-43-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 May 2024 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-43-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Finite state machines Hybrid Meetup #43 took place 2024-05-28 at Gridfuse, Hauptpost Leipzig. We had a great presentation about a lightweight (~200 LOC), open source state machine library written in Go: ekstatic — presentation slides (PDF)
The use case in the context of RAIDA is the modelling of workflows, composed of a number of steps (and the loose coupling of business logic with state transistions). The library is flexible, but the limits of the Go type system require to resort to any (which will defer some type checks to runtime).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #43 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-43-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-43-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For meetup #43 on Tuesday May 28, 2024 19:00 CET we are thrilled to collaborate again with Gridfuse, a renewable energy startup in the heart of Leipzig with the mission to help deliver a world where renewable energy sources become the main source of power on the global grid.
 By fusing together multiple individual renewable sources through software and intelligent algorithms, we unite them into a force that can transform our global energy system.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOLAB 2024</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/golab-2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2024 11:30:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/golab-2024/</guid>
      <description>GOLAB 2024 GOLAB, The International Conference on Go is a wonderful event that brings together developers from Europe and beyond in Florence, Italy since 2015 and which will take place 2024-11-11 to 2024-11-13 this year, featuring a discovery and deep dive track as well as workshops on introductory and advanced topics. Find out more:
 Conference homepage: golab.io GOLAB on Twitter GOLAB YouTube Channel, recordings from previous years  We partnered with GOLAB and are excited to share discount codes for tickets 🎟️ — just drop by our next event!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #42 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-42-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 May 2024 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-42-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Fast Things First Hybrid Meetup #42 took place 2024-04-30 at CHECK24 Leipzig Office at Altes Landratsamt. We had two talks that revolved around Go and performance: Patrick Vahl gave a great overview about SIMD in Go and what is possible (and not possible), today. Examples from the talk can be found here: Crash129/go-simd-example. A few points from the talk:
 performance gains can be significant try to isolate SIMD as much as possible   The difficulty with a general purpose approach to SIMD [&amp;hellip;] is that the performance can be dramatically different on different processors.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Faster XML processing in Go</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/faster-go-xml-processing/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 12:00:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/faster-go-xml-processing/</guid>
      <description>Prelude Go supports XML processing in the standard library package encoding/xml. The Marshal and Unmarshal function will use a Encoder and Decoder under the hood, as these are more general.
With a Decoder it is possible to iterate over a large number of XML elements and to deserialize data in a way that will limit memory consumption. Here is a playground example for using a decoder to repeatedly parse elements from a Reader: efY60PYLFm8.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #42 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-42-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Mar 2024 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-42-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For meetup #42 on Tuesday Apr 30, 2024 19:00 CET we&amp;rsquo;re excited to again collaborate with CHECK24, which will host this meetup at their Leipzig office, located at Tröndlinring 3, 04105 Leipzig. CHECK24 has a diverse tech stack that includes a growing number of Go projects.
We will have two presentations: one about SIMD and Go, by Patrick Vahl and one about the 1BRC (1 Billion Row Challange) and Go performance tips by Martin Czygan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #41 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-41-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-41-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Go 1.22 and more Hybrid Meetup #41 took place 2024-02-27 at Basislager Leipzig. We reviewed some updates in Go 1.22, especially the sharing bug fix in for loops and the enhanced routing pattern.
Go tools for genai models There is no shortage of tooling and applications for LLM and generative AI in general, and increasingly, these tools abstract the model access away to you can use remote or local models with the same code (and easily switch between different providers).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #41 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-41-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2024 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-41-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For meetup #41 on Tuesday Feb 27, 2024 19:00 CET we&amp;rsquo;ll discuss what&amp;rsquo;s new in Go 1.22.
You can join us in person at Basislager Leipzig (free drinks) or remotely via Google Meet (BYOD).
See you!
 Join us to discuss all things Go, and similar things!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #40 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-40-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-40-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Domain Driven Data Oriented Design Hybrid Meetup #40 took place 2024-01-30 at Basislager Leipzig and we had a great presentation by Bill Kennedy from Ardan Labs about Domain Driven Data Oriented Design. A recording of the talk is available at our YouTube Channel.

All code shown in the talk is available at: ardanlabs/service.
Just a few notes from the talk:
 CRUD is boilerplate domain-driven design comes with a cost but can help to keep larger projects structured and maintainable one way to limit data exposure per domain is to create a relational view per domain example of an opaque type from the repo is user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #40 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-40-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2024 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-40-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Happy 2024! For meetup #40 on Tuesday Jan 30, 2024 19:00 CET we are thrilled to have Bill Kennedy, Gopher Pioneer and Managing Partner at Ardan Labs joining us (remotely) to talk about Domain Driven, Data Oriented Design.
Domain driven design has been tackling complexity in the heart of software since Eric Evans&#39; classic 2003 book, while emphasizing data in programming has many facets, from caring about caches, over treating data as first-class citizen (cf.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2023</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Dec 2023 02:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/2023/</guid>
      <description>In 2023 large language models and generative AI captured many minds - fewer know that the official Go repository included code to train a statistical language model (and to respond to prefixes) since Aug 17, 2011, which is based on chapter 3.1 from The Practice of Programming (1999), which in turn took inspiration from Dewdney, A. K. (1989), COMPUTER RECREATIONS. Scientific American, 260(6), 122–125 (the trace continues further to Shannon, 1951 and Markov, 1913)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎄 Drinkup #39 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-39-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Dec 2023 20:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-39-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Drinkup notes Meetup #39 took place 2023-12-19 at Cantona Leipzig and these were just some of the talking points.
 without extra libraries, schema validation in JSON is minimalistic (e.g. json schema); could cue help? malloy is an experimental data modeling language over relational stores direnv is a nice shell helper for 12-factor-style appu time is not just a line, it&amp;rsquo;s bound (cf. chrony) test your latencies: aws, gcp, or just the internet eventbridge/kubernetes at serverless office hours interesting, dedicated code assistant for ansible: Ansible Lightspeed  Next year will probably bring yet another wave of hyper-focussed LLM-based code comprehension tools (beside hyper-focussed niche, local, custom-trained LLMs for dedicated tasks, in general).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>🎄 Drinkup #39 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-39-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Nov 2023 15:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-39-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For meetup #39 on Tuesday Dec 19, 2023 19:00 CET we will meet at Cantona Leipzig (OSM) for drinks.

Join us to discuss all things Go, cloud, AI, past, future and beyond. See you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #38 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-38-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Nov 2023 22:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-38-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>A cache is worth a thousand searches Hybrid meetup #38 took place 2023-11-20 19:00 at CHECK24 Leipzig Office.
We had a great presentation from Fabian about building a mission critical query caching database (MemoryDB) in Go and the challenges involved.
One challenge is the variety of query parameters and nearly overlapping values and ranges. A key for performance is to express various parameter values (e.g. date boundaries) with the help of BitMaps, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #38 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-38-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Nov 2023 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-38-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For meetup #38 on Tuesday Nov 21, 2023 19:00 CET we&amp;rsquo;re excited to collaborate with CHECK24, which will host this meetup at their Leipzig office, located at Tröndlinring 3, 04105 Leipzig. CHECK24 uses Go in production at scale.
We&amp;rsquo;re having two presentations:
 Fabian will present about a Go project developed at CHECK24 Martin (Leipzig Gophers) will give a lightning talk about running and using large-language models (LLM) locally with the help of Go tools (following up on some topics discussed in #35)  We&amp;rsquo;ll meet:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go at devopenspace 2023</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-devopenspace-2023/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 00:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-devopenspace-2023/</guid>
      <description>devopenspace is a regular, classic unconference on software engineering and related topics - this year, there are a few Go and cloud related workshops as well! See the agenda for more details.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #37 notice</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-37-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Sep 2023 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-37-notice/</guid>
      <description>Free Form Meetup #37 Since starting Leipzig Gophers almost four years ago we always aimed at connecting people and to learn about interesting Go projects and we had a lot of fun organizing that. Meetup #37 on 2023-09-26 aimed to be a free-form event, that is an event without a defined agenda with an opportunity to meet and discuss.
We&amp;rsquo;ll try to sharpen the free-form event format in the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #36 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-36-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-36-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Cut Cloud Complexity with Encore Hybrid meetup #36 took place 2023-06-20 19:00 at Basislager Leipzig.
We had a great presentation from André Eriksson about Encore - a platform written in Go and for Go for radically simplifying cloud-native backend development.
Beside motivation and overview, André live-coded an uptime monitoring service, ran it locally and deployed it onto Google Cloud within a few minutes. A recording of the talk is available on YouTube!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #36 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-36-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-36-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For meetup #36 on Tuesday Jun 20, 2023 19:00 CET we&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to welcome André Eriksson, software engineer and founder of Encore, a startup building the next generation platform for rapid backend development.
 Building cloud-native backends and distributed systems can involve large amounts of complexity and repetitive boilerplate.
 Encore is a backend development platform and infrastructure SDK designed to simplify building such backend. Encore provides a declarative approach to managing cloud infrastructure directly in application code, based on static analysis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In The Stack</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/bigcode-in-the-stack/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 May 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/bigcode-in-the-stack/</guid>
      <description>In The Stack The AI space develops fast, with one cornerstone being the availability of open datasets for model development and training. Code from golang-leipzig is part of The Stack (20 Nov 2022):
 a 6.4 TB dataset of permissively licensed source code in 358 programming languages.
 Five of our repositories are included in the 25.74 GB of source code (spread across 4,730,461 files) written in Go included in this dataset.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #35 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-35-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Apr 2023 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-35-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Cgo experiments Hybrid meetup #35 took place 2023-04-18 19:00 at Basislager Leipzig and was all about Cgo.
Cgo allows to bridge C and Go. From C, we can connect to other languages, like C++, too. Use cases are legacy code or performance. Implementing a pseudo-random walk (using an LCG) in both Go and C shows that C can be up to 4x faster for this particular task.
C 1 -1 29.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #35 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-35-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Apr 2023 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-35-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For meetup #35 on Tuesday Apr 18, 2023 19:00 CET we&amp;rsquo;ll have a lightning talk about CGO, which allows to call C code from Go.
We&amp;rsquo;ll meet
 in person at Basislager, Peterssteinweg 14, 04107 Leipzig and online via meet.jit.si/LeipzigGophers35.  Join us to discuss all things Go and CGO. Onsite: presenters&#39; laptop NumCPU free drinks!
See you!
  &amp;ldquo;cgo is not go&amp;rdquo; as mural painting &amp;ndash; Stable Diffusion</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLT23</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/clt23/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/clt23/</guid>
      <description>CLT23 We briefly presented at the annual Chemnitz Linux Days (CLT) conference on 2023-03-11. The topic was Sustainability and Security in the Go ecosystem, collecting a few thoughts starting from the ACM Queue article Surviving Software Dependencies (2019).
Keywords: security, data breach, dependency management, distributed package management, OSV, vulnerability scanning.
We prepared a demo for the vanity URL import supported by Go package system - check out clt23 or try:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #34 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-34-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-34-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Go 1.20 Hybrid meetup #34 took place 2023-02-21 19:00 at Basislager Leipzig and was all about Go 1.20 (similar to previous years, where we looked at Go 1.14, 1.16, 1.18 - #9, #16, #25).
We had two great presentations:
 A rundown of most novelties in Go 1.20: Go 1.20 updates, including many examples &amp;ndash; thanks, Andreas! &amp;hellip; and Go 1.20 Coverage Profiling Support for Kubernetes Apps, a walkthrough on how to use Go 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #34 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-34-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jan 2023 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-34-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For meetup #34 on Tuesday Feb 21, 2023 19:00 CET we&amp;rsquo;ll have a few lightning talks and experience reports about some upcoming, exciting Go 1.20 features, e.g. related to coverage, error handling, end-to-end tests in containerized environments and more.
We&amp;rsquo;ll meet
 in person at Basislager, Peterssteinweg 14, 04107 Leipzig and online via meet.jit.si/LeipzigGophers34.  Join us to discuss all things Go 1.20 and beyond.
See you!
  Concurrency is not parallelism as mural painting &amp;ndash; Stable Diffusion</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2022</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2022 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/2022/</guid>
      <description>From an email exchange in November 2009 (a few weeks after the first presentation on Go):
 It seems to me that these functions [append, copy] are not useful if we figure out a way to implement generics. Not necessarily a strong argument against them, I suppose, but do we want to introduce new builtin functions if we may not need them?
 About 4500 days and many proposals later, Go 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Drinkup #33 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-33-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2022 20:00:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-33-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Drinkup Notes We met 2022-12-20 19:00 at Café Cantona, with no specific Go agenda, for a great exchange of ideas and experiences - too many to capture them in a blog post, so here&amp;rsquo;s just a fraction of the topics we passed (slightly categorized):
Reading list  Grokking Functional Programming - a very readable introduction to the topic; more academic angles include the classic Out of the tar pit or Purely Functional Data Structures (always nice to find references to this book in code) in 04/2022, a JS version of SICP (1984) came out: SICP JS edition, there&amp;rsquo;s an open access version, too Podman in Action, container tools with a nice Unix backdrop the classic, albeit just five year old DDIA 100 mistakes in Go and how to avoid them - actionable advice for Go code improvements  Software General  ISO 28500:2017, aka WARC is how you can capture the web - and there are many libraries and tools around this format, just to name a few: Heritrix, brozzler, webrecorder, warcprox, replayweb.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Winter Drinkup #33 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-33-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2022 19:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-33-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #33 on Tuesday Dec 20, 2022 19:00 CET will be an offline-only (AFK) meetup &amp;ndash; it&amp;rsquo;s getting cold, so we&amp;rsquo;re meeting for warm drinks at Cantona Leipzig (on OpenStreetMap).

Join us to discuss all things Go, past, future and beyond. See you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #32 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-32-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Nov 2022 13:00:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-32-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Gridfuse x Leipzig Gophers Leipzig Gophers #32 took place on 2022-11-29 19:00 CET and we had a great meetup at Gridfuse&#39; new office in the heart of Leipzig. Gridfuse was founded in 2022 and builds software to bundle renewable energy sources (wind, solar, &amp;hellip;) to react to market prices - in Germany and Europe.
Predicting future energy prices is one key component, and renewables pose their own set of challenges since they depend more on external factors (like the weather, and more&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #32 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-32-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Nov 2022 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-32-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Gridfuse x Leipzig Gophers For meetup #32 on Tuesday Nov 29, 2022 19:00 CET we&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to collaborate with Gridfuse, a start-up in the heart of Leipzig!
Jörg from Gridfuse will give a presentation on how they use telegraf (code) to persist timeseries data in influxdb and will also talk about their open source contributions to the telegraf nats plugin.
 Gridfuse is a 2022-founded start-up that has made it its mission to swift the balance of power in the energy domain.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #31 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-31-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Oct 2022 13:00:31 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-31-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Personal Cloud On 2022-10-18 19:00 CEST we had our #31 meetup, this time at Basislager Coworking and with a hybrid setup (that still needs some improvement, but we&amp;rsquo;re getting there).
Max Eusterbrock and his colleague Aavash Shrestha told us about The personal cloud and the monster that makes it. In this presentation they gave us a preview on one of their new platforms that provides one-click hosting of applications, which they demonstrated with the deployment of a note taking service knotro.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #31 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-31-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Oct 2022 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-31-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Clouds, Monsters and Streams For meetup #31 — on Oct 18, 2022 19:00 CEST — we&amp;rsquo;re happy to have (remote) guests from Berlin! We&amp;rsquo;ll have a short talk and demo by personal cloud builders deta.sh: The personal cloud and the monster that makes it.

We&amp;rsquo;re excited to find out, what makes deta fly!
Depending on time and interest, we have two other lightning talk registrations:
 Reading the last bytes of a stream in Go &amp;ndash; blog post A quick summary of Cloud Native Go (O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media, 2021) (postponed)  Hybrid Meetup This meetup will be hybrid:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid meetup #30 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-30-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Sep 2022 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-30-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Secure data with immudb - a fast, immutable database Leipzig Gophers Hybrid Meetup #30 took place 2022-09-20 19:00 CEST at Lancaster University Leipzig Campus.
We had a great presentation by Dennis Zimmer and Bartłomiej Święcki (GitHub) from CodeNotary about their cutting edge, open source, immutable database project immudb.
Presentation slides are available here:

Originally, the CodeNotary team looked at blockchains to implement the idea of tamperproof data store - but found that they could build something more performant.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hybrid Meetup #30 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-30-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-30-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
immudb For meetup #30 — on Sep 20, 2022 19:00 CEST — we&amp;rsquo;re thrilled to welcome Dennis Zimmer and Bartłomiej Święcki from Codenotary, who will talk about their open source database project immudb.

 immudb is a ledger database that has been developed with performance, scalability and versatility in mind [&amp;hellip;]
  Data stored in immudb is cryptographically coherent and verifiable. Unlike blockchains, immudb can handle millions of transactions per second, and can be used both as a lightweight service or embedded in your application as a library.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Drinkup #29 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-29-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Jul 2022 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-29-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>All things Go and beyond We met on 2022-07-14 at Soltmann Bar and it was great to see everyone in person and also to welcome new Gophers.
In September, we hope to follow up with an in-person meetup featuring a presentation from immudb:
 immudb is database with built-in cryptographic proof and verification. It can track changes in sensitive data and the integrity of the history will be protected by the clients, without the need to trust the server.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Summer Drinkup #29 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-29-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Jun 2022 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-29-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Summer&amp;rsquo;s getting hot, so let&amp;rsquo;s meet AFK for cold drinks on Jul 14, 2022 19:00 CEST at Soltmann Bar (OSM). We&amp;rsquo;ll have some Go swag to give away!

We have no specific agenda. We hope for good weather and look forward to meet you all in person, after all.
See you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #28 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-28-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Jun 2022 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-28-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Errors and Glamour Meetup #28 took place on 2022-06-21 19:00 CEST virtually and was one of our most visited meetup to date - thank you all for dropping by.
We had a short presentation Never forget to handle errors, rediscovered the 1000th time by Leandro from Lightmeter (gitlab, job) about a few ways to handle errors in Go. The compiler does not complain about unchecked errors, but some linters do.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #28 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-28-invititation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jun 2022 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-28-invititation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For meetup #28 — on Jun 21, 2022 19:00 CEST — we&amp;rsquo;ll have two lightning talks:
 Never forget to handle errors, rediscovered the 1000th time &amp;ndash; Leandro Santiago from lightmeter.io A glance at glamorous command line apps with charm &amp;ndash; Martin Czygan  Join us to discuss all things Go via Google Meet: https://meet.google.com/mpb-ypdi-est - see you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>State of Go at Leipzig Software Craft June 2022 Meetup</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/software-craft-state-of-go-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2022 00:12:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/software-craft-state-of-go-2022/</guid>
      <description>We will be talking about the State of Go in 2022 at the classic and incredible Leipzig Software Craft Meetup (née Softwerkskammer) in June 2022.
Go is 12 years old at this point in time. The last years brought quite a few changes into the Go ecosystem and language and we want to highlight some of those, specifically:
 Generics Go Modules and dependency management Ecosystem developments and more …  Who, when and where?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #27 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-27-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 May 2022 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-27-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Algorithm Challenge Meetup #27 took place on 2022-05-10 19:00 CEST and was virtual again and we had an interesting problem-solving live-coding challenge.
Slides and code: gitlab.com/telo_tade/prefix_suffix_arrays
Problem  You are given a list of numbers. Find its longest slice that sums to zero.
 First, clarify:
 Is it a consecutive list of numbers? What kind of numbers, and how many?  We collaboratively went from a naive O(n^3) solution to a slightly improved O(n^2) one using an auxiliary data structure: a prefix sum array.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #27 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-27-invititation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 May 2022 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-27-invititation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For meetup #27 — on May 10, 2022 19:00 CEST — we&amp;rsquo;ll have an interactive coding session around Go generics.
We start with a problem and will develop two versions, one with and one without generics.
For a refresher on Generics see:
 refs/spec https://go.dev/doc/tutorial/generics https://www.klingt.net/articles/go-1-18-with-some-fuzzing-and-a-focus-on-generics.html (see also: #25)  Join us to discuss all things Go via Google Meet: https://meet.google.com/wxm-argz-hqh</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #26 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-26-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2022 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-26-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Type Signatures and Cloud Storage Meetup #26 was virtual again and we were glad to meet Gophers from Leipzig and beyond. We had a two short talks and code walkthroughs on type signatures and rclone, a cloud storage tool.
Type Signatures How would you generate a unique fingerprint for a type? A fingerprint that would change, even if the name of the type stays the same, but e.g. fields in a struct are renamed, added or removed?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #26 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-26-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Apr 2022 07:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-26-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Join us for meetup #26 Apr 26, 2022 19:00 CEST via Google Meet: https://meet.google.com/weh-dtvn-gpk.
We&amp;rsquo;ll have two lightning talks:
 Calculating Type Signatures The rsync for the cloud era: Rclone  Other lightning talks and project discussion are welcome - join us to discuss all things Go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #25 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-25-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-25-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Go 1.18 and generics Meetup #25 was virtual and we were glad to have an international audience again.
We had a great presentation about the upcoming Go 1.18 release, including generics and fuzzing:
 Go 1.18 with some fuzzing and a focus on generics  As always, Go 1.18 will include lots of smaller tweaks and improvements, like a new debug/buildinfo package, which
 provides access to information embedded in a Go binary about how it was built,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #25 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-25-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Feb 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-25-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Join us for meetup #25 Feb 22, 2022 19:00 CET via Google Meet: https://meet.google.com/fqi-juff-zwy.
We&amp;rsquo;ll take a closer look at the upcoming Go 1.18 release, especially generics.
Thanks to the generous support from JetBrains and Manning Publications, we can share a JetBrains personal subscription and an ebook - 100 Go Mistakes and How to Avoid Them - with our participants.
Join us to discuss all things Go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 29 Dec 2021 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/2021/</guid>
      <description>Unfortunately, most of the meetups were remote-only again in 2021 - however, on the plus side:
 we started the year with a new Leipzig Gopher mascot - thanks @klingtnet we grew from 194 to 324 members in just eleven months 📈 we had nine events, eight online, one offline (#20) we had presentations from two German startup companies (#22, #23) we started a YouTube channel (thanks @embano1), recorded three great talks (18 subscribers, 330+ views) 📹 we had a first (X-mas 🎄) quiz night (#24) on Go and some Go gotchas and found great sponsors like Jetbrains, O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media, Manning Publications and About You (jobs) 🎁 we continued to have people joining from around the world, which is incredible 🌐 we had a lovely time hosting the meetup and hope you had that too  Thanks everyone for participating, we hope to see you again in 2022!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #24 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-24-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 01:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-24-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Quiz night! Thanks everyone for joining our quiz night at virtual meetup #24, Dec 21, 2021; we got through 16 of our 24 prepared questions - from easy to hard. Most prizes are already on their way.
A special thanks 💕 to our sponsors:
 O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media Manning Publications About You (check out jobs) Jetbrains  Happy holidays!
 Join our meetup to get notified of upcoming events!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #24 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-24-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Dec 2021 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-24-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For virtual meetup #24 - scheduled 2021-12-21, 19:00 CET we&amp;rsquo;re inviting you to test your knowledge of Go. We&amp;rsquo;re planning a fun quiz and we&amp;rsquo;re going to have a few prizes, too!
As any language, Go has dark corners and gotchas but also some lesser known features.
We&amp;rsquo;re lucky to have Jetbrains, Manning Publications, O&amp;rsquo;Reilly Media and AboutYou sponsoring vouchers and books for this event. Additionally, we are giving away Go pins and posters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #23 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-23-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Nov 2021 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-23-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Summary Meetup #23, Nov 23, 2021, originally planned on-site at Sciendis, moved online again, due to the pandemic regulations.
We had two input presentations, one about Go in a startup environment at Sciendis and reasons why Go may be a good choice. And one lightning talk about a data web service.
Go in a startup environment Sciendis develops a React Native application called Wundera with the backend service being written in Go, in a classic cloud setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #23 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-23-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Nov 2021 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-23-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Corona emergency ordinance (SächsCoronaNotVO §7 2021-11-19) becoming effective on Monday forces us to move this meeting online. Our talk schedule stays the same.
Join us for meetup #23 Nov 23, 2021 19:00 CET via Google Meet: https://meet.google.com/sym-ohzu-spb.
 We&amp;rsquo;re always interested in connecting with the local Go community and we&amp;rsquo;re thrilled that for meetup #23 on Nov 23, 2021 Sciendis reached out to us and offered to host an event at their site.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hackolaus #2: Hack for Good</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/hackolaus-2-hack-for-good/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Nov 2021 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/hackolaus-2-hack-for-good/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
   Update 2021-11-04: Cancelled: See hackolaus.de for new dates.
  Update 2021-11-03: Hackolaus #2 may be cancelled due to local pandemic regulation; please follow updates at the event site.
   We would like to invite you to a special hackathon event this year: Hackolaus #2 - running from Nov 19 to Nov 21, 2021 at Basislager Leipzig.

 When the nights get longer and the weather outside is frightful, we need some warmth in our hearts.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #22 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-22-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 Oct 2021 14:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-22-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Confidential Computing with Go We had a great presentation by Moritz Eckert from edgeless systems about Confidential Computing with Go, and especially ego.dev, a modified Go compiler and additional tooling which allows you to run code within a trusted execution environment like Intel® SGX enclaves with zero code changes.
Here&amp;rsquo;s a recording of the talk, code walkthroughs and Q&amp;amp;A:

A few highlights from the talk:
 a trusted execution environment can be implemented in various ways, Intel SGX being one that is usable today (with others in development, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #22 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-22-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Oct 2021 11:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-22-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
For virtual meetup #22 - scheduled 2021-10-26, 19:00 CEST - we&amp;rsquo;ll have an interesting presentation on a security related topic: Confidential Computing with Go.
Join us via Zoom.
 Confidential Computing with Go Confidential computing is a new security paradigm that protects data not only at rest or in transit but also in use. A hardware-based trusted execution environment provides an isolated area, a secure enclave within a CPU, that protects sensitive data while being processed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #21 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-21-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Oct 2021 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-21-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Concise Encoding We had a great presentation about Concise Encoding, a proposed encoding standard that aims to be human and machine friendly.
 Presentation: go-concise-encoding  Here&amp;rsquo;s a recording:

Concise encoding is element-oriented (similar to e.g. JSON) and tries to solve some issues in existing standards, such as lack of types, performance and security (one similar format is Amazon Ion).
In prerelease stage, feedback is highly appreciated, a reference implementation written in Go exists at:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #21 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-21-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Sep 2021 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-21-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #21 will take place Tuesday, Sep 28, 2021 19:00 CEST and will be virtual again. We&amp;rsquo;ll use Zoom (find the link on the event page or below):
 https://us02web.zoom.us/j/81869277732?pwd=ZldmeHp0eWs0N1YyTE94OUo2Z01vdz09  We will have an input presentation by the author of Concise Encoding about the project and its Go reference implementation. Concise encoding is a
 friendly data format for human &amp;amp; machine.
 It addresses a modern dilemma:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #20 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-20-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 24 Jul 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-20-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>We keep this short, as there would be too many interesting things to mention that come up, if curious and fun people meet.
Just to name a few things: 1417599138796118016, Cue and Automerge (JS), &amp;hellip;
A couple of people had distant memories of Pascal, which also influenced Go e.g. in declarations or conditions without parentheses.
Many people use vscode or vim, but there are also some dedicated Go IDEs, e.g. GoLand or liteide:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AFK Summer Meetup #20 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-20-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-20-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #20 will take place Tuesday, Jul 20, 2021 18:30 CEST and we&amp;rsquo;ll meet outside for a cold drink - specifically at Cantona Leipzig (on OpenStreetMap).

We have no specific agenda. We hope for good weather and look forward to meet you all in person, after all.
See you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #19 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-19-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jun 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-19-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Journey to the Center of Kubernetes Meetup #19 took place Jun 22, 2021 19:00 CEST, and was virtual again. Michael Gasch gave an input presentation on etcd and did a deep dive into its role in the container-orchestrator kubernetes.
The talk is based on a blog post: Onwards to the Core: etcd. A shell transcript can be found here:
 https://git.io/JnQ1n  We learned about the API of etcd, its data model, key value stores layouts, append-only storage and compaction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #19 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-19-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-19-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #19 will take place Tuesday, Jun 22, 2021 19:00 CEST and will be virtual again. We&amp;rsquo;ll use Zoom (find the link on the event page or below):
 https://us02web.zoom.us/j/84547890514?pwd=eXIzdXU2RGJmWmw4NzVjb0VMazZxZz09  We&amp;rsquo;ll have an input presentation about a core distributed systems project: etcd.
 etcd is a strongly consistent, distributed key-value store that provides a reliable way to store data that needs to be accessed by a distributed system or cluster of machines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #18 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-18-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 May 2021 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-18-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Seeking Data Meetup #18 took place May 25, 2021 19:00 CEST, and was virtual again. We continued the data and storage supertopic for this year had a lightning talk called Seeking Data.
We looked at a few patterns when working with data, e.g. I/O considerations, what kernel hackers think about the memory hierarchy, working with large scale data at rest, or how to speed up container startup times (via lazy pulling).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #18 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-18-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 May 2021 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-18-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #18 will take place Tuesday, May 25, 2021 19:00 CEST and will be virtual again. We&amp;rsquo;ll use Zoom (find the link on the event page or below):
 https://us02web.zoom.us/j/84647419671?pwd=Z0l2aDBrNWtqZDR5azRVbkRmeHdyUT09  We&amp;rsquo;ll have lightning talk on a data topic.
As always, other lightning talks or contributions are welcome.
See you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #17 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-17-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-17-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>(Fuzzy) Matching with command line tools and Go Meetup #17 took place Apr 20, 2021 19:00 CEST, and was virtual again (crossing one year of virtual meetups). We had a lightning talk on a data engineering topic:
 (Fuzzy) Matching with command line tools and Go  How to build a graph dataset with about 1B edges from semi-structured data? With Taco Bell style programming, you can reuse (UNIX) command line tools and combine it with a few custom Go programs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #17 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-17-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 19 Apr 2021 16:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-17-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #17 will take place Tuesday, Apr 20, 2021 19:00 CEST and will be virtual again. We&amp;rsquo;ll use Zoom (find the link on the event page or below):
 https://us02web.zoom.us/j/88430151082?pwd=QzlFWlhKaUJKajFxcXRqRkpYYzNSdz09  We&amp;rsquo;ll have lightning talk on data deduplication with Go.
As always, other lightning talks or contributions are welcome.
See you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #16 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-16-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-16-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Go 1.16 Meetup #16 was all about Go 1.16 (which was released after the meetup).
We had an informative breakdown of the updates coming in this release, the full slides can be found here:
 A quick tour of Go 1.16  A few highlights are: the go tool is now module aware by default, ioutil gets deprecated, support for file embedding (we talked about that in #14) and there is a new io subpackage io/fs, defining among other things interfaces for filesystems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #16 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-16-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Feb 2021 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-16-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #16 will take place Tuesday, Feb 16, 2021 and will be virtual again. We&amp;rsquo;ll use Zoom (find the link on the event page or below):
$ curl -sL https://git.io/Jt0pk | base64 -d We&amp;rsquo;ll have input presentations on the upcoming Go 1.16 release and the generics proposal.
Note: This time the meetup will be all about the number sixteen, i.e. this will be the sixteenth time we come together, on the 16th of February and there will be a presentation about the next big Go release that is Go 1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New year, new dates, new logo!</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/welcome-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Jan 2021 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/welcome-2021/</guid>
      <description>Thanks everyone for joining our meetup (we currently have 194 members), connecting, sharing experiences and projects in 2020. A positive side-effect of remote meetups during a pandemic is that people join from all over the world - we were happy to have people tuning in from South America and Asia this year.
We expect a remote only meetup for the foreseeable future. So far we fixed six dates for 2021, and they will all be on Tuesdays this year.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #15 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-15-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Dec 2020 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-15-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Concurrent woes We had two input presentations, both involving concurrent constructs.
First, we heard from the author of package waitgroup about problems with concurrent code, waitgroups and shutdowns (especially in cloud native and serverless scenarios). The basic problem: At shutdown time, you want to be graceful, but at the same time enforce a hard timeout on a number of processes running (and potentially joining in a wg.Wait).
Enter package waitgroup which allows to preempt running goroutines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #15 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-15-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Dec 2020 12:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-15-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #15 will take place today Dec 18, 2020 and will be virtual again. We&amp;rsquo;ll use Zoom (find the link on the event page or below):
$ curl -sL https://git.io/JLBe8 | base64 -d We&amp;rsquo;ll have two input presentations:
 On a WaitGroup wrapper, including testing strategies. On a tiny library - parallel that allows to write parallel filters fast.  As always, other lightning talks or contributions are welcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #14 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-14-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Nov 2020 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-14-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>File Embedding We had a great input presentation on file embedding, which allows to ship additional files within a binary.
How do you put files into a binary? There a numerous tools, some of them limited, some of them with large feature sets.
Is it time for Yet Another File Embedding Tool? Yes!
That such a tool can be simple and easy to use is shown by klingtnet/embed.
Misc  awsls is a tool that uses code generation to simplify AWS command line interactions we side-tracked into note-taking, and found out that people use all kinds of journal software, from OneNote, plain text files, custom software and plain paper notebooks   Join us next time!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #14 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-14-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Nov 2020 10:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-14-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #14 will take place Nov 13, 2020 and will be virtual again. We&amp;rsquo;ll use Zoom (find the link on the event page or below):
$ curl -sL git.io/JkIVG | base64 -d We will have an input presentation on file embedding - a popular technique to make deployments and workflows easier. Many tools exists today, as can be seen in #35950. Have you ever wondered, which of these to use?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #13 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-13-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Oct 2020 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-13-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Today we had two input presentations:
 Haystack and seaweedfs: https://github.com/miku/haystack Functional Options Pattern: https://github.com/embano1/funcy-ops  Haystack The haystack talk gave an overview about an early Facebook photo storage system and a Go project inspired by it, called seaweedfs. The seaweedfs project is great, as it is developer friendly, scales up and down and is easy to use out of the box. It offers an S3 compatible API and a FUSE filesystem option.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #13 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-13-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-13-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #13 will take place today, Friday Oct 16, 2020 19:00 CEST and will be virtual again. We&amp;rsquo;ll use Zoom (find the link on the event page or below):
$ curl -L is.gd/GOIxW7 | base64 -d We have a short talk on seaweedfs, a key value store written in Go and inspired by the Facebook Haystack paper (back when FB only had 20PB of image data).
Beyond a key-value store seaweedfs offers various storage access methods on top, e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #12 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-12-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-12-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>We had a short talk about HTTP proxies in Go. As expected, Go supports the usual environment variables, like HTTP_PROXY, HTTPS_PROXY and NO_PROXY - and you can easily customize the proxy selection, as we saw in an example code walkthrough of an ip rotation proxy.
The x/net package contains support in x/net/http/httpproxy.
A couple of fun facts from the talk:
 The first book on HTTP proxies was published in 1998: &amp;ldquo;Web Proxy Servers&amp;rdquo; by Ari Luotonen (CERN), who also wrote a web proxy tunneling draft.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #12 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-12-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Sep 2020 16:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-12-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #12 will take place today, Thurdays, Sep 17, 2020 19:00 CET and will be virtual again.
We have a talk about HTTP proxies. You&amp;rsquo;ll discover one CVE you never heard of and we see what the author of curl says on SO, why curl does not strictly follow the HTTP RFC.
See you!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #11 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-11-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 May 2020 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-11-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Kubeflow  The data science process is not free of friction, especially when acquiring, preparing and cleaning data. But even when data is readily available, one might want to use it to train a number of ML models to perform model selection.
And what happens, if an update is available and the whole process needs to be run again? Optimally with a tested model that is put into production in a canary deployment workflow?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #11 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-11-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Apr 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-11-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Meetup #11 will take place on Friday, May 15, 2020 19:00 CET and will most likely be virtual again (we will share the zoom link here and on the meetup event page).
This time, we&amp;rsquo;re excited to look at software built with Go. Our main topic will be the cloud native machine learning toolkit: kubeflow.
Kubeflow - A follow up Leveraging Kubernetes for Data Science purposes is still a burden for many users these days.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #10 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-10-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Apr 2020 10:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-10-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 The sync package  Virtual Meetup #10 took place on Friday, April 17, 2020, 19:00 CEST via Zoom (thanks to saschagrunert and CNCF).
Michael prepared a great overview of the sync and x/sync packages, which implement concurrency related facilities (concurrency is hard with either classical approaches or CSP, as we learned from a presentation last year at meetup #2).
The overview included among other things a bug hunt in a counter example and a benchmark of the builtin map and sync.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Virtual Meetup #10 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-10-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Mar 2020 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-10-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
The global coronavirus pandemic puts limitations on all aspects of societal life. At the time of our last meetup, two people were infected in Germany, as of this announcement, we are at 57.298.
The Go community addresses resulting issues in a blogpost on the pandemic.
For Meetup #10 on Friday, April 17, 2020, we still would like to bring people together, in form of a shorter, virtual meetup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #9 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-9-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Feb 2020 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-9-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Go 1.14  Meetup #9 took place on Friday, February 21, 2020, 19:00 CEST at Basislager.
We looked at changes coming in the upcoming Go 1.14 release, which is is expected to be released in February 2020.
The slides can be found here:
 Slides, Repo  
There are many improvements, just one of them is lower-cost defer statements.
The proposal can be found here:
 Proposal: Low-cost defers through inline code, and extra funcdata to manage the panic case  Recommended podcast: gotime/112.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #9 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-9-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2020 20:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-9-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Our first 2020 meetup is scheduled for Friday, Feb 21, 2020 19:00 at Basislager Leipzig.
We&amp;rsquo;ll have a 30 min input presentation about Golang&amp;rsquo;s standard library package net/http, especially extension points and customization options for clients and alternative implementations.
UPDATE: There will also be a presentation about Go 1.14 (which will be released next week) and what we already know about Go 1.15 and beyond. Slides and sources can be found here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thanks and to the future!</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/bye-2019/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2019 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/bye-2019/</guid>
      <description>Thanks everyone for joining our meetup (we currently have 111 members), being curious about Go and for sharing your projects and topics in 2019. We hope you had as much fun as we had.
The future of Go seems bright, the language and ecosystem being so versatile, cloud-friendly and popular.
Let&amp;rsquo;s explore this future together in 2020!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #8 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-8-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2019 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-8-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Anatomy of a Go module proxy  The Go packaging story started many years ago with GO15VENDOREXPERIMENT and a myriad of tools for managing dependencies. And, annoyingly GOPATH was one of the main obstactles for people getting started with Go. Since Go 1.11, we have experimental support for Go modules.
A new component related to modules is the module proxy. A bit of history, internals and pitfalls has been compiled by klingtnet into a great talk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #8 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-8-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Oct 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-8-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Our next meetup is scheduled for Friday Nov, 15 2019, 19:00 at Basislager.
We will have input presentations on two topics:
 A custom deployment utility for Pull Requests written in Go Go module proxy internals and pitfalls  As always, please bring your projects, questions, findings. Spontaneous lightning talks and other inputs are welcome, too.
 Hallo, 世界!
Unser nächstes Meetup findet am 15. November 19:00 im Basislager statt.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #7 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-7-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 28 Sep 2019 14:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-7-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Concurrency in Go  Concurrency is hard, but the primitive building blocks of CSP in Go - goroutines and channels - can make things simpler.
We glanced at the six chapters of Concurrency in Go, and learned a bit about the problem setting, goroutine sizes, context switch times and patterns.
The notes can be found here:
 Notes on Concurrency in Go  In the book, the perf tool is used to benchmark context switch times of the kernel - and to compare it with context switch times in the Go scheduler.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go and Cloud Native Meetup Split</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-cloud-native-split/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2019 21:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-cloud-native-split/</guid>
      <description>🔗 TL;DR  We will reshuffle meetups a bit: The current Go and Cloud Native meetup will be split up, into a Go focussed meetup (we will keep the Meetup group, just rename it) and a dedicated Cloud Native Meetup - which might be merged with the growing Linux Meetup Leipzig.
If you have not attended Linux Meetup Leipzig yet and you are interested in Enterprise Linux and Cloud Native topics, please join.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #7 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-7-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Aug 2019 13:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-7-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界!
Our next meetup is scheduled for Sep, 27 2019, 19:00 at Basislager.
Back after summer break we jump right into a core Go topic: concurrency.
We will summarize the book
Concurrency in Go: Tools and Techniques for Developers
and present and discuss techniques - from theoretical to practical aspects.
As always, please bring your projects, questions, findings. Spontaneous lightning talks and other inputs are welcome. too.
 Hallo, 世界!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Decentralized Storage Summit Berlin</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/decentralized-storage-summit-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2019 00:12:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/decentralized-storage-summit-berlin/</guid>
      <description>In Meetup #4 we learned about a Go project using the Lightning Network. Many more projects in the Cryptocurrenty space use Go, such filecoin, subprojects from sia and many more.
If you are excited about these technologies, why not attend the Decentralized Storage Summit at TU Berlin on Friday, August 23, 2019?
Here&amp;rsquo;s a link to a discount code to get in for free:
 https://www.eventbrite.com/e/decentralised-storage-summit-tickets-62719912948?discount=DC2  Enjoy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #6 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-6-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-6-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Where to Go?  The Berlin Go User Group celebrates its eighth birthday next week. Our meetup just completed its first ½ year - so far, we touched upon quite a few of the initial topic ideas.
As for Go conferences, Golab is an annual international Go conference, which will have its 4th edition this October. We have two free tickets for you - if you are interested, just drop me a line.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #6 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-6-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-6-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界! Last minute invitation for meetup #6.
This will be an open event - please bring your projects, questions, findings. Lightning talks and other inputs are welcome. too.
We have two free tickets for the Golab 2019 Go conference in Florence, Italy - so if you are interested, just drop by.
 Hallo, 世界! Last Minute Einladung zu Meetup #6.
Offenes Treffen, eigene Projekte, Themen, Tools, Fragen sind willkommen, ebenso lightning talks und andere Inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #5 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-5-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Jun 2019 01:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-5-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Bits from the IO package  The IO package is a central package in the standard library, as it provides (among other things) two main interfaces:
 io.Reader io.Writer  In a lightning talk we dug a bit into the package:
 Slides (PDF) Repo  The IO model is simple and powerful (and reminds one of UNIX pipes).
🔗 Automate the Web with chromedp  In a code walkthrough we explored chromedp, a pure Go library talking the Chrome devtools protocol.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #5 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-5-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Jun 2019 12:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-5-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Hello, 世界! For meetup #5 we will have two lightning talks:
 Beautiful (and strange) IO  A short overview of the io package and its interfaces and possible strategies for custom implementations. Plus some a few examples of implementations you might not have seen before.
 Controlling a headless browser with Go.  A quick look at web automation with Go and Chrome.
As always are also looking for lightning talks, presentations or other kinds of inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #4 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-4-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2019 22:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-4-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>🔗 Lightning Network Micropayments  Go is popular in the crypocurrency space. The well-rounded standard library and great support for networking applications might be one reason. In Meetup #4 Philipp presented an introduction to Bitcoin, Lighting Network and a Go project, that makes micropayments for API usage really simple: ln-paywall.
The presentation is available as PDF.
An http middleware takes care of creating invoices per request, a complete example can be implemented in a few lines.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #4 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-4-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2019 11:45:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-4-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Meetup #4 is scheduled for Friday, May 17, 2019, 19:00 CEST at Basislager.
Hello, 世界! For meetup #4 we will have a presentation Philipp, about the Lightning Network by especially about a Go middleware that allows to monetize Web APIs on a per-request basis. Without accounts, credit cards, payment providers - in a pure P2P fashion. We will have a short refresher on Bitcoin as well.
As always are also looking for lightning talks, presentations or other kinds of inputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go at Spartakiade 2019 Berlin</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-at-spartakiade-2019-berlin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2019 09:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-at-spartakiade-2019-berlin/</guid>
      <description>Spartakiade is a regular, developer-centric conference in Berlin. This year it will host over twenty full day workshops, with topics ranging from data science, 3D, docker, kubernetes, and also a few programming language introductions, among them F#, Python, Purescript &amp;ndash; and Go!
There will be two Go workshops (in English or German, depending on the audience):
 Apr, 27 2019, 10-17: Kann weniger mehr sein? Eine praktische Einführung in die Programmiersprache Go (Can less be more?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #3 wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-3-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 23:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-3-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Meetup #3 took place on Friday, April 12, 2019, 19:00 CEST at Basislager. We are now officially part of the Go Developer Network (GDN, currently 103 groups with 47418 members in 37 countries), which was announced in March 2019.
 The GDN is a collection of Go user groups working together with a shared mission to empower developer communities with the knowledge, experience, and wisdom to build the next generation of software in Go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Meetup #3 invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-3-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2019 13:15:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-3-invitation/</guid>
      <description>Meetup #3 is scheduled for Friday, April 12, 2019, 19:00 CEST at Basislager.
We will take a closer look at Go modules for dependency management. We also have one potential proposal for a lightning talk with the cryptic title &amp;ldquo;Ramen Linux&amp;rdquo;.
As always, please bring your own code, projects, ideas, Go and Cloud-Native questions and let&amp;rsquo;s discuss them. See you there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second meetup wrap-up</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/second-meetup-wrapup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2019 13:15:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/second-meetup-wrapup/</guid>
      <description>Our second meetup took place yesterday (2019-03-15) at Basislager Leipzig, here&amp;rsquo;s a short wrap-up:
  miku gave a lightning talk about generating Go structs from JSON and XML documents, e.g. via JSONGen or zek. Code generation is not perfect, but can save you time.
  Michael presented the paper Understanding Real-World Concurrency Bugs in Go, which compares bug classes by analyzing popular open source projects like BoltDB, etcd, Docker and Kubernetes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second meetup invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/second-meetup-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Mar 2019 15:20:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/second-meetup-invitation/</guid>
      <description>For our second meetup tonight, we have two lighting talk proposals:
 Turn data into Go struct - how to easily work with complex XML documents and JSON data with Go Glance at the io package and some io.Reader implementation, that you may not have seen before - how to implement your own reader and some examples of useful (sometimes strange) implementations from existing projects  Please bring your own code, projects, ideas, Go and Cloud-Native questions and let&amp;rsquo;s discuss them.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go at Coding Leipzig Chapter Four</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-at-coding-leipzig-chapter-four/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Feb 2019 15:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-at-coding-leipzig-chapter-four/</guid>
      <description>A last minute tip for today: There will be a quick introduction to Go at Coding Leipzig Chapter Four meetup tonight at Basislager:
 Michael Panzer | GoBasics in 30 Minutes   Michael is co-organizer of Leipzig Golang and Cloud-Native Meetup and show us the basics of Golang in only 30 minutes. He has prepared a bunch of useful examples.
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Second meetup: Call for Input</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/second-meetup-call-for-input/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Feb 2019 17:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/second-meetup-call-for-input/</guid>
      <description>The second meetup is scheduled for Friday, March 15, 2019, again 19:00 CET at Basislager. Do you have an idea for a presentation, lightning talk, code review or any other activity? Let us know until March, 1 2019 by filling out this form:
 https://goo.gl/forms/btBm0tInUp25XdUi2  You can also send us ideas by email!
For some inspiration, there is a list of topics, we discussed at the first meetup.
See you there!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Launched 🚀</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-launched/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Feb 2019 00:15:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/meetup-launched/</guid>
      <description>We launched! The first meetup took place yesterday (2019-02-08) at Basislager. A dozen gophers, programmers, devops developers, cluster admins and curious individuals followed our invitation.
A good mix of backgrounds, experience levels and professional contexts lead to lively discussions around Go, the language, microservices, company cultures, adoption, streaming, cruise ships, conference impressions, book tips, distributed denial-of-service attacks, kubernetes operators and much more. Thanks for joining us, we think we&amp;rsquo;re off to a good start!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First meetup invitation</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/first-meetup-invitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:12:45 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/first-meetup-invitation/</guid>
      <description>First event announced.
Hello, 世界! This is our first meetup, for anybody interested in the Go programming language and Cloud-Native technologies. We would like to know, what you would expect from the meetup, what you would be interested in and talk about the roadmap for the next months. For this first event, we do not have a special topic, so it’s more a come together to get to know and connect the community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>New Golang and Cloud-Native Meetup</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/new-meetup-group/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jan 2019 12:45:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/new-meetup-group/</guid>
      <description>We now have an meetup.com profile, upcoming events will be announced there. Thrilled to see people expressing interest in this.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Go makes the frontpage</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-heise-frontpage/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:10:01 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/go-heise-frontpage/</guid>
      <description>On 22, Jan 2019, Go made it to the frontpage of heise.de, with an introductory article about the language:
 Einstieg in Go (German)  After a brief historical overview, the authors jump right into various channels types. They also highlight struct embedding and interfaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First meetup date is fixed</title>
      <link>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/first-meetup-date-is-fixed-2019-02-08/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jan 2019 00:14:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://golangleipzig.space/posts/first-meetup-date-is-fixed-2019-02-08/</guid>
      <description>The first Golang and Cloud-Native Meetup will take place on Friday, 8th of February 2019 starting 19:00 at Basislager Leipzig, ground floor.
Are you using Go? Are you curious about Go? Are you a cloud architect? You are working on an interesting project that you would like to share? Or maybe you just want to meet some fellow Gophers in your city? Then, by all means, consider dropping by.
This will be our first meeting and there will be plenty of room to participate and shape this meetup going forward.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
